# Rachel Bach

04320 767 99 | rachelbach93@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rachel-bach

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a career changer who completed a coding bootcamp and is working toward becoming a software developer.

I'm currently undertaking a placement at NAB as a Software Tester, ensuring the quality and reliability of the GRC application, which enables employees and third parties to engage with the website efficiently.

In previous role I've worked as a Support Engineer, I gained experience with Agile methodologies (Scrum) and collaborated with the DevOps team to run data pipelines (Jenkins & Harness), monitor AWS services (EC2 & RDS), document processes for non-technical stakeholders, and contribute to the codebase for pipeline development.

I'm also passionate about UX/UI design and enjoy building websites. I completed a React Development course at General Assembly and used React to build my portfolio and personal projects. My experience in customer service gives me a unique perspective on software development, with a deep understanding of user needs and expectations.

## SKILLS

- JavaScript, Java, Ruby
- React, Node.js, Spring Boot, Mockito, Junit
- HTML, CSS, Styled Components, Responsive Design
- PostgresSQL, MySQL
- REST, JSON
- Git, GitHub, AWS, Jira, Google DevTools, Jenkins, qTest, Docusaurus,
   JQ, VIM Text Editor, Unix, Excel, Figma

## CERTIFICATES

- React Development (2023 General Assembly Bootcamp Melbourne)
- AWS Cloud Quest (2023\_AWS Training and Certification\_Online)
- Full Stack Web Development (2023\_LeWagon Bootcamp Melbourne)
- UX/UI Digital Product Design (2021\_KeyFrame Multiple School\_Vietnam)

## **EDUCATION**

University of Economics Ho Chi Minh City
Bachelor of Commerce in International Business

2011 - 2015

#### EXPERIENCE

# NAB (Placement)

Software Tester

- Developed test cases for new features and updates in the GRC application, relying solely on requirement specifications
- Upon deployment, executed test cases and raised defects where the new build did not align with requirements
- Gained experience in Resilience Risk Management

## Support Engineer

- Migrated data from the Global Data Warehouse to the internal processing zone for further processing
- Collaborated with the DevOps team to run data pipelines using Jenkins and Harness, supporting microservices deployments.
- Extracted details of AWS services (i.e. EC2, S3) using JQ and the AWS CLI for analysis
- Monitored microservices' performance on AWS CloudWatch, tracking key metrics such CPU and memory utilisation
- Developed a new Jenkins job to allow users without AWS access to start, stop, or pause EC2/RDS instances, providing operational flexibility
- Documented data extraction/export processes by using Airflow for non-technical stakeholders using Docusaurus, ensuring clarity and ease of use
- Gained experience working with a variety of tools and tech stacks, including databases (PostgreSQL, DBeaver), DevOps (Jenkins, Harness, AWS), and more

## FDM Group

Nov 2023 - Present

IT Consultant

- Successfully completed Technical Development Training Program
- Developed a full stack web application using React, SpringBoot and MySQL Workbench to manage and monitor internal computers' software versions in different offices
- Developed a REST API using SpringBoot and MySQL Workbench to store data from internal systems

## MobiFone

Sept 2016 - May 2022

CX Specialist

- Supported Account Manager to optimise customer satisfaction and provided data reports according to the requirements
- Coordinated with internal teams to relay customer feedback and improve service offerings
- Implemented and led frequent promotional events for existing customers through the call centre team (e.g., offering a 15% discount on packages for loyal customers)